<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>University of Florida Bureaucracy | UFHCC BCB-SR Bioinformatics Wiki</title><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/uf-bureaucracy/</link><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/docs/uf-bureaucracy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>University of Florida Bureaucracy</description><generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><image><url>http://localhost:1313/media/icon_hu_bb893f6dc6eaf6fe.png</url><title>University of Florida Bureaucracy</title><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/uf-bureaucracy/</link></image><item><title>IACUC - Animal care &amp; use</title><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/uf-bureaucracy/iacuc-forms-and-training/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/uf-bureaucracy/iacuc-forms-and-training/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Start this process early as approval will take a few weeks.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="important-notes">Important Notes&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Include the protocol number in the subject line of any emails to IACUC: &lt;strong>201808839&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
CC Morgan and Glenda in your communications to relevant offices.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="register-with-myiacuc">Register with myIACUC&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Go to &lt;a href="https://my.iacuc.ufl.edu" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://my.iacuc.ufl.edu&lt;/a> and log in with your Gatorlink username and password and register as &amp;ldquo;study staff&amp;rdquo;. (If you are not on campus, you will need to use VPN to access my.iacuc.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You will receive a notice when you have been approved.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let Glenda know you have been approved and she will file a modification in the protocol to add you.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="forms">Forms&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Fill out the EH&amp;amp;S &lt;a href="http://webfiles.ehs.ufl.edu/ACForm.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">AC Form&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Supervisor (for Portal): Morgan (352-294-2082; &lt;a href="mailto:skmorgane@ufl.edu">skmorgane@ufl.edu&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fiscal Contact: Daniel Deep (352-846-0578; &lt;a href="mailto:ganderindan@ufl.edu">ganderindan@ufl.edu&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Has the Payment Authorization Form been submitted? Choose YES (Morgan usually does this)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Type of Animal Contact: 5 (Handles, restrains, etc.)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Frequency: monthly&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Description: rodent trapping and tagging, collection of rodent morphometric data&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Check all the boxes under rodents, and specify: mice, rats, squirrels&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Complete all pages, add name at top of each page, and remember to sign&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Email to Supervisor to sign and turn in (email completed form to &lt;a href="mailto:OccMedClinic-RiskAssessment@ahc.ufl.edu">OccMedClinic-RiskAssessment@ahc.ufl.edu&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Notify the IACUC office (&lt;a href="mailto:iacuc@research.ufl.edu">iacuc@research.ufl.edu&lt;/a>) that the form has been completed.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="training">Training&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="aalas">AALAS&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Complete the AALAS modules available at: &lt;a href="http://www.aalaslearninglibrary.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener">http://www.aalaslearninglibrary.org&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&amp;ldquo;Working with the IACUC (For Ag and Wildlife)&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&amp;ldquo;Working With The Laboratory Mouse&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&amp;ldquo;Working With The Laboratory Rat&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Note: Each training has 20 modules (~1 hour/training). Going through practice questions will help you pass the final exam at the end of each training since some practice questions are asked in the final exam.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Optional: Download the CEU and Exam certificates for each training, for your own perusal.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>If you don&amp;rsquo;t already have an account:&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Visit &lt;a href="https://iacuc.ufl.edu/secure/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://iacuc.ufl.edu/secure/&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Open the &amp;ldquo;Instructions for Working With IACUC Training&amp;rdquo; panel.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click on the link for first-time users. Click on &amp;ldquo;AALS Login&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Open &amp;ldquo;Tracks&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;UF Researchers - IACUC Training Modules&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Once these requirements have been completed, please notify the IACUC office at &lt;a href="mailto:iacuc@research.ufl.edu">iacuc@research.ufl.edu&lt;/a>. Please make sure to include the protocol number in the subject line of any emails. If you have any questions, please contact the IACUC office at (352) 273-9535.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="responsible-conduct-of-research-rcr">Responsible Conduct of Research (RCR)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Required for NSF sponsored projects&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Follow instructions here: &lt;a href="https://research.ufl.edu/rcr/rcr-training/citi-rcr-training/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://research.ufl.edu/rcr/rcr-training/citi-rcr-training/&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="once-completed">Once Completed&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Refresher courses will be required periodically.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>myUF Market</title><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/uf-bureaucracy/myufmarket/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/uf-bureaucracy/myufmarket/</guid><description>&lt;p>Quick Hints and Tips for Using myUF Market&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="guides">Guides&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Access the market by logging into myUFL, going under &lt;em>My Self Service&lt;/em>, then selecting&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="myufmarket">myUFMarket&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>This website has a link to guides for most of what you will need to do: &lt;a href="http://hr.ufl.edu/learn-grow/just-in-time-training/myufl-toolkits/purchasing/#sims" target="_blank" rel="noopener">myUF Market Instruction Guides&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="misc-information">Misc. Information&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>To ship something off-campus: In the &lt;em>Select a new shipping address&lt;/em> search bar, type &amp;ldquo;One Time&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Pcards</title><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/uf-bureaucracy/pcards/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/uf-bureaucracy/pcards/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="rules-of-use">Rules of Use&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>P Card info is at &lt;a href="https://procurement.ufl.edu/uf-departments/procurement-cards-pcards/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">UF Procurement&lt;/a>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://procurement.ufl.edu/uf-departments/procurement-cards-pcards/transactions/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Travel Guidelines&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://procurement.ufl.edu/uf-departments/procurement-cards-pcards/procedures/allowable/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">List of Allowable purchases&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://wec.ifas.ufl.edu/resources/ufgo-pcard-forms/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">WEC P Card FORMS&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Single transaction limit – The amount one single charge cannot exceed. Ours is $2,000.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cycle limit – The amount that can be charged in the weekly cycle (Wed through Tue). Ours is $10,000.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Purchases cannot include sales tax if in Florida or with vendors with UF agreement (eg Amazon).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Can be used for travel costs (flights, car rentals, gas for business travel, etc)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>CANNOT be used to purchase food or drinks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>NEVER EVER EVER use for personal use. There is no &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll payback the University for this&amp;rdquo;. This includes putting gas in a personal vehicle, even if it&amp;rsquo;s for work travel.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When you&amp;rsquo;re leaving UF, cancel your pcard by just emailing them (&lt;a href="mailto:pcard@ufl.edu">pcard@ufl.edu&lt;/a>) on your last day, and they will have you shred the card yourself.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="getting-a-pcard">Getting a PCARD&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>You need to go through pcard training. This involves watching a number of videos.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Step 1: Go to myUFL, then navigate to My Self Service &amp;gt; Training and Development &amp;gt; myTraining. To search for the PCard courses, click in the Activity Search box, then enter the appropriate course name or number.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>As a PCARD holder, you will need to take the following courses: UFGO500 and UFGO100&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When you finish your training submit the &lt;a href="https://forms.office.com/Pages/ResponsePage.aspx?id=-KBNDTFKdk2s5gpiMx4bhGicOwDMKeFOrgQpJC5WLa1UOVNKQkdRWkVEODdRMzQ4NUdYVjFGOE1CMiQlQCN0PWcu" target="_blank" rel="noopener">WEC PCARD APPLICATION FORM&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once WEC receives your request the following process will take place:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>WEC will fill out the Pcard Application with the information you provide in this form&lt;/li>
&lt;li>WEC will collect required signatures&lt;/li>
&lt;li>WEC will submit Pcard Application to pcard team on your behalf (pcard team requires Dept approval)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pcard team will notify you when the card has been ordered&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can expect to receive the card in about 15 days after.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You will receive an email from WEC instructing you to pickup your pcard&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In reality, processing takes a few weeks to a month. You may need to go in and specifically ask for it if you don&amp;rsquo;t get an email.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once you receive the card, activate it and set a PIN:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Call 8882338855&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Your account number is the credit card number&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Your &amp;ldquo;Verification ID&amp;rdquo; is 0 followed by your UFID&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The phone number associated with the account is 352 392 1331.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>This information is in the email from the PCard office that tells you your application was approved. You won&amp;rsquo;t get a separate piece of mail with a PIN.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="general-info">General Info&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This section is for general info commonly needed for PCard Purchases&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Billing Address: University of FLorida, PO Box 110430, Gainesville FL 32611-0430&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Billing Phone Number: 352-392-1331.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>PCard are now Chip and Pin cards, so you may need your PIN when using the card in stores.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you use with a PIN, the vendor may ask for a p number/project code/somesuch thing. You can just say the name of the project it&amp;rsquo;s for, it&amp;rsquo;s not a specific value.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="using-the-pcard">Using the Pcard&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>So you&amp;rsquo;re taking the big step and actually going to use the PCard. Not to scare you but the PCard is a big responsibility and the University takes using them correctly very seriously, so make sure to follow the flowchart below!&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Are you purchasing for yourself, or someone else?&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Never loan anyone your P Card, or give them your P Card information to use - this could result in a suspension&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You are welcome to purchase items or travel for others, just do it yourself. There are fields on the travel and P Card forms to provide information on who you&amp;rsquo;re purchasing for and why.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Are you making an item purchase (i.e. an object like a keyboard, paper, etc) or a travel related purchase (i.e. flight, registration, etc)&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Item Purchase: Jump to Step 3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Travel Purchase: You need to also have a Travel Authorization submitted so that the travel costs can be associated with the travel approval. Go to the Travel page and follow those instructions. Before proceeding to step 3.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Are you in a store or buying on the web?&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Store: Jump to step 4&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Web: Make sure that the site is not going to charge you sales tax. If it is you must stop immediately. There are other ways of purchasing from online vendors. If the vendor is on myUF MarketPlace (found on myufl) then you can follow &lt;a href="http://hr.ufl.edu/wp-content/uploads/instructionguides/Using%20PCard%20in%20myUF%20Market.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">these guidelines&lt;/a>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>AMAZON - STOP! - Amazon items must be purchased via the punchout on myUF MarketPlace. Do not use your P Card on Amazon.com, you could get your P Card suspended.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Otherwise, talk to Glenda about purchase orders through the department. If you are still making your online purchase, billing address can be found under general info. Proceed to step 4.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You are in a store. Are you in Florida or out of state?&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Florida: The University of Florida is exempt from paying sales tax and gets irritated about paying it. You need to make sure you have the tax exempt card with you so the store knows not to charge you sales tax. You should have received a card with your pcard but if not you can get one &lt;a href="http://www.fa.ufl.edu/wp-content/uploads/disbursements/fa-pds-cce.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here&lt;/a> . Show them your card and proceed to step 5.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Out of State: Stay calm and carry on. Sales tax charges are ok if purchases are made out of state. Proceed to step 5.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>I have my thing, now what?&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>You have three, yes 3, days to submit your receipts to WEC.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Complete the &lt;a href="https://forms.office.com/Pages/ResponsePage.aspx?id=-KBNDTFKdk2s5gpiMx4bhGicOwDMKeFOrgQpJC5WLa1UMFZaV0ZaQjRIOFRSTE1RMUtXNTFWTkFXMyQlQCN0PWcu" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PCARD RECEIPT SUBMISSION FORM&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Most of the form is self-explanatory. But putting some time into the description and justification will make your life easier. The staff really likes it if pcard holders are very clear about what the purchase is so taking time to fill in that section in the form goes a long way (i.e. if the vendor name is confusing or the items seem like they shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be allowed on the grant).
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>You can only put items on a sponsored project (a specific project-related grant) if the item will without question only be used for that project. Computers and computer supplies are especially difficult to justify. There is always department money that can be used for these items if it&amp;rsquo;s questionable.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you&amp;rsquo;re purchasing travel for someone else, make sure you put it on a chartfield they are allowed to work on (usually one they are paid from)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Please describe how the items will be used for the chartfield being charged.&lt;/em>: Take care to provide a thorough justification of why the item is needed
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>No: computer supplies&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Yes: Cables and communication equipment will be used in the field to communicate with project team members on project goals&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Chartfield to Charge&lt;/em>: You can get this from Glenda if you don’t know it&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Benefit to Funding Source&lt;/em>: Provide a clear explanation as to how the items will benefit the chartfield you listed above
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>No: field work&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Yes: Tools for field site maintenance and saftey&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Attach a picture of the receipt at the end of the form.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you are traveling, I would recommend taking a picture as soon as you get the receipt in your hand. You don&amp;rsquo;t want to lose receipts. Trust me.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you buy fuel for a rental car, you need to include the rental agreement number in the email.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Did you lose your receipt?&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>People will be unhappy with you but it is not the end of the world. You need to fill out this &lt;a href="http://www.wec.ufl.edu/resources/fiscal/Replacement_Receipt_Form_2009-08.doc" target="_blank" rel="noopener">form&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The form requires your supervisor (Ethan or Morgan) to sign it. You will receive the stank eye from a variety of people. You will survive.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>I took longer than 3 days to submit my documentation&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>You have likely gotten several emails from concursolutions warning you you have overdo expenses, just go ahead and submit the form ASAP.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If WECfiscal sends you get a notification that you are out of compliance on your P Card let Glenda, Morgan or Ethan know.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="temporarily-increasing-purchasing-limit">Temporarily increasing purchasing limit&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>It is possible to temporarily increase the purchasing limit on your card if needed.
To do this complete the &lt;a href="https://forms.office.com/Pages/ResponsePage.aspx?id=-KBNDTFKdk2s5gpiMx4bhGicOwDMKeFOrgQpJC5WLa1UNTIxR01JV0ZHMlVFM1cyRkdJTFVGNEg3NCQlQCN0PWcu" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ONE-TIME PCARD LIMIT INCREASE REQUEST FORM&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rental Cars</title><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/uf-bureaucracy/rental-cars/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/uf-bureaucracy/rental-cars/</guid><description>&lt;p>UF faculty and staff can get discounted rates on rental cars for &lt;a href="https://procurement.ufl.edu/contracts-2/rental-vehicles/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">personal&lt;/a> &lt;strong>and&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://www.concursolutions.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">business&lt;/a> purposes. The discount code is immediately applied when booking directly through UFGO (for business travel) or the Gator Perks (for personal travel) website.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Graduate students can get the same discounted rates for &lt;a href="https://procurement.ufl.edu/contracts-2/rental-vehicles/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">business purposes&lt;/a> &lt;strong>only&lt;/strong>. A staff badge/ID is required upon pick up for employment verification. If not available, a letter from a department chair confirming the employment status of a graduate student can be used.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Your PCard CAN be used to purchase fuel for a rental vehicle (for business use only of course). Reference the rental agreement in on the PCard purchase form.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Travel</title><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/uf-bureaucracy/travel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/uf-bureaucracy/travel/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="basic-travel-info">Basic Travel Info&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cfo.ufl.edu/initiatives/uf-go/travel/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">General UF Go travel page&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://wec.ifas.ufl.edu/resources/ufgo-travel-forms/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">WEC Travel Forms&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="important-policies-to-know">Important policies to know&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Do not pay for gas with a Pcard unless you have a state vehicle or rental. Fuel in a personal vehicle can only be paid through a mileage calculation.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The amount of per diem you can claim is based on your actual travel times. (eg If you are flying, it is based on your actual departure and arrival times.)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can only get reimbursed for tipping taxi/Uber/Lyft drivers up to 20%.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>There are special rules for conferences, see the conference section below.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It is possible to add personal travel to UF travel, see the personal travel section below.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>See the &lt;a href="https://procurement.ufl.edu/uf-departments/procurement-cards-pcards/alpha/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">A-Z Guide&lt;/a> for more&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The travel process at UF can be broken down into 3 major steps:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Travel Request&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Booking travel&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Travel Expense Report (TER, being reimbursed for travel)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="travel-request">Travel Request&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Fill out the &lt;a href="https://forms.office.com/Pages/ResponsePage.aspx?id=-KBNDTFKdk2s5gpiMx4bhGicOwDMKeFOrgQpJC5WLa1URVFSV0ExNkExTzFNM1EzNUxZTlZMRjZRNyQlQCN0PWcu" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TRAVEL REQUEST / BLANKET TRAVEL REQUEST FORM&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most of the form is self-explanatory.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Please provide justification for essential travel: Take care to provide a thorough justification of why the travel is needed
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>No: field work&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Yes: Travel to field site to collect data and perform maintenance&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Chartfield to Charge: You can get this from Glenda if you don&amp;rsquo;t know it&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Benefit to Funding Source: Provide a clear explanation as to how the travel will benefit the chartfield you listed above
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>No: field work&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Yes: LTREB data collection for monitoring and forecasting&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Meals (Unless travelling internationally): Choose
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Meal rate - Domestic (36.00 Per Day)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Meal type - Personal Funds&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Estimated Meal Amount - 36*days (this is the maximum, actual amount will be calculated after travel)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>International Travel&lt;/strong>: See &lt;a href="https://www.fa.ufl.edu/directive-categories/international-travel/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">INTERNATIONAL TRAVEL&lt;/a> to ensure you&amp;rsquo;re following all the additional guidelines necessary.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>WEC Fiscal Staff will email you a copy of report when ready to approve.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You do NOT need to wait for the request to be approved to start booking your travel (unless it is conference travel).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="booking-travel">Booking Travel&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>With few exeptions, you must book all UF-related travel through UFGO&amp;rsquo;s booking agent.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Log into UFGO (concursolutions.com).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ensure you already have your profile (top right) set up with your contact info, P Card info, any loyalty programs you are a part of (airline, hotel, car rental), and your travel preferences.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Go to Travel (in the top menu bar).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Under TRIP SEARCH in the left pane, ensure you have selected &amp;lsquo;Business Travel&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;Booking for myself&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Book flights, hotel and/or rental car all on the same itinerary.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Under Method of Payment, choose AirCard for flights, Pcard for everything else.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="ter">TER&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Once all your travel is completed and you have all your receipts ready to upload, fill out the &lt;a href="https://forms.office.com/Pages/ResponsePage.aspx?id=-KBNDTFKdk2s5gpiMx4bhGicOwDMKeFOrgQpJC5WLa1UNVpHSk4wN1pHWktOTzBSWVkzSDhFTVdRMCQlQCN0PWcu" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TRAVEL EXPENSE REPORT / OUT OF POCKET REIMBURSEMENT FORM&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>WEC Fiscal Staff will email you a copy of report when ready to approve.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Log into UFGO (concursolutions.com).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Go to Expense (in the top menu bar).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Current reports will be shown in the REPORT LIBRARY. Choose the name matching your notification email.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Check everything carefully and make sure everything is entered correctly.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If everything is correct, click Submit Report.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="conference-travel">Conference Travel&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The PCard may be used to pay registration fees for conferences, conventions, or seminars. This includes those where the registration fee includes meals or social events. Registration reciepts must be itemized so UF can determine whether meals/social events/lodging are included in the fee or can be charged separately.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Optional events, those with separate fees, cannot be paid via PCard. Optional events must be paid for by the traveler.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Travel Requests, required for all travel relating to conferences/conventions, must be done BEFORE making charges. The Travel Request number must be written on receipts and other supporting payment documentation.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="personal-travel-before-or-after-uf-related-travel">Personal Travel Before or After UF-related Travel&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You are welcome to add some personal travel to a UF-related work trip. You will just need to submit the information in your TA and TER. During your entire period of travel, you will need to designate each day as a &amp;lsquo;work&amp;rsquo; day or &amp;rsquo;non-work&amp;rsquo; day. When booking in UFGO, document the itinerary and price for what you would have booked if personal travel were not included, and include this as an attachment in your TER.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>University of Florida Benefits</title><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/uf-bureaucracy/benefits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/uf-bureaucracy/benefits/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="postdocs">Postdocs&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="health-plans">Health plans&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://hr.ufl.edu/benefits/new-employees/eligibility-and-enrollment/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Available health plans for postdocs&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://hr.ufl.edu/wp-content/uploads/health-plan-compare.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Information on the general benefits for different health plans&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="retirement-plan">Retirement plan&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://hr.ufl.edu/benefits/retirement/fica-alternative-plan/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Primary&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://hr.ufl.edu/benefits/retirement/voluntary-savings-plans/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Optional supplementary&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>University of Florida Vehicles</title><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/uf-bureaucracy/uf-vehicles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/uf-bureaucracy/uf-vehicles/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="non-uf-individuals-driving-uf-vehicles">Non-UF individuals driving UF vehicles&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The general rule is that only UF employees can drive UF vehicals.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, there are several ways to override this default:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Registered volunteers can drive UF vehicles&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Individuals contracted through UF can drive UF vehicles if the contract explicitly states that the contracting organization is responsible for providing insurance related to operating the vehicles.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>UF has a system for purchasing supplementary insurance for individual vehicles to allow them to be driven by specific identified individuals who are not employees.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Talk to your departmental operations person for (1) (currently Cameron Carter for those of us in WEC).
Brian Hunt in &lt;a href="https://www.ehs.ufl.edu/about/contacts/occupational-safety-risk-management/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Environmental Health &amp;amp; Safety&lt;/a> can help with the details in both cases (2) and (3).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>WEC Staff</title><link>http://localhost:1313/docs/uf-bureaucracy/wec-staff/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/uf-bureaucracy/wec-staff/</guid><description>&lt;p>If something seems is going wrong, especially if you have some scary warnings holding on your tuition and fees status, this is the page for you!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-if-i-receive-a-message-from-the-bursar">What if I receive a message from the Bursar?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Don&amp;rsquo;t worry (too much), since that&amp;rsquo;s something more common than expected. However, you may need to contact &lt;strong>Daniel Deep&lt;/strong> at &lt;a href="mailto:ganderindan@ufl.edu">ganderindan@ufl.edu&lt;/a>. He is a great guy, and will try to fix your issues in no time!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-if-i-am-getting-worried-about-travel-reimbursement">What if I am getting worried about travel reimbursement?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Take into consideration that tons of folks are traveling too, and hence delays are normal. The rule of a thumb in this case is to send a reminder email to &lt;strong>WECfiscal&lt;/strong> (&lt;a href="mailto:WECFiscal@ifas.ufl.edu">WECFiscal@ifas.ufl.edu&lt;/a>) a month or so after you sent them your Travel Expense Report. If you don&amp;rsquo;t receive any answer yet, send another email after two weeks, this time CCing your adviser. Another good advice in this space is to get in touch with &lt;strong>Donna Dyer&lt;/strong> (&lt;a href="mailto:dkb@ufl.edu">dkb@ufl.edu&lt;/a>). She Has been working here for 30 years, is well prepared, and always useful. Ideally, if you are in office, you better go and talk to her in person: that will solve your problems way faster!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>